1999
DELAWARE
Statehood: December 7, 1787 Coin Release: January 4, 1999 Release Order: 1 Total Mintage for Circulation: 774,824,000
Design: The Delaware quarter’s reverse celebrates Caesar Rodney’s historic horseback ride to the Continental Congress in 1776 to cast the
deciding vote in favor of independence.
Pennsylvania
Statehood: December 12, 1787 Coin Release: March 8, 1999 Release Order: 2 Total Mintage for Circulation: 707,332,000
Design: The Pennsylvania quarter depicts the “Commonwealth” statue, an outline of the state, the state motto, and a keystone reflecting the
state’s nickname, “The Keystone State.”
New Jersey
Statehood: December 18, 1787 Coin Release: May 17, 1999 Release Order: 3 Total Mintage for Circulation: 662,228,000
Design: The New Jersey quarter depicts General George Washington and members of the Colonial Army crossing the Delaware River en
route to very important victories during the Revolutionary War. The design is based on the 1851 painting by Emmanuel Leutze,
“Washington Crossing the Delaware.”
Georgia
Statehood: January 2, 1788 Coin Release: July 19, 1999 Release Order: 4 Total Mintage for Circulation: 939,932,000
Design: The Georgia quarter design incorporates several symbols associated with the traditional, yet very diverse southern state. The coin’s
reverse incorporates the state’s geographical outline, motto, tree and nickname.
CONNECTICUT
Statehood: January 9, 1788 Coin Release: October 12, 1999 Release Order: 5 Total Mintage for Circulation: 1,346,624,000
Design: The Connecticut quarter features “The Charter Oak”: an integral part of Connecticut’s heritage and existence. Heroic Captain
Joseph Wadsworth saved Connecticut’s Charter from the hands of the British by concealing it in a majestic white oak, which came to
be known as “The Charter Oak.”
2000
MASSACHUSETTS
Statehood: February 6, 1788 Coin Release: January 3, 2000 Release Order: 6 Total Mintage for Circulation: 1,163,784,000
Design: The Massachusetts quarter features a design of “The Minuteman,” a famous statue that stands guard at The Minuteman National
Historical Park in Concord, Massachusetts.
Maryland
Statehood: April 28, 1788 Coin Release: March 13, 2000 Release Order: 7 Total Mintage for Circulation: 1,234,732,000
Design: The Maryland quarter highlights the striking dome of the Maryland Statehouse surrounded by White Oak leaf clusters and the
nickname “The Old Line State.”
South Carolina
Statehood: May 23, 1788 Coin Release: May 22, 2000 Release Order: 8 Total Mintage for Circulation: 1,308,784,000
Design: The South Carolina quarter depicts key state symbols – a Palmetto Tree, the Carolina Wren and the Yellow Jessamine. An outline of
South Carolina, the nickname “The Palmetto State” and a star indicating the capital, Columbia, form the quarter’s background.
New Hampshire
Statehood: June 21, 1788 Coin Release: August 7, 2000 Release Order: 9 Total Mintage for Circulation: 1,169,016,000
Design: The New Hampshire quarter honors one of the state’s most unique natural attractions, “The Old Man of the Mountain.” The state
motto, “Live free or die,” and nine stars, reflecting New Hampshire as the ninth state to ratify the Constitution, complete the design.
Virginia
Statehood: June 25, 1788 Coin Release: October 16, 2000 Release Order: 10 Total Mintage for Circulation: 1,594,616,000
Design: The Virginia quarter honors Jamestown, Virginia, the Nation’s first permanent English settlement. The design features the three
ships, Susan Constant, Godspeed, and Discovery, that brought the first settlers to Jamestown in 1607.
Appendix: Coin Design and Description
23
2001
New York
Statehood: July 26, 1788 Coin Release: January 2, 2001 Release Order: 11 Total Mintage for Circulation: 1,275,040,000
Design: The New York quarter features the Statue of Liberty superimposed over an outline of the state along with the inscription “Gateway to
Freedom.” Also incorporated into the state outline is a line tracing the Hudson River and the route of the Erie Canal.
NORTH CAROLINA
Statehood: November 21, 178 Coin Release: March 12, 2001 Release Order: 12 Total Mintage for Circulation: 1,055,476,000
Design: The North Carolina quarter highlights the famous 1903 photograph of the “First Flight,” the first successful airplane flight that took
place in Kitty Hawk, North Carolina.
RHODE ISLAND
Statehood: May 29, 1790 Coin Release: May 21, 2001 Release Order: 13 Total Mintage for Circulation: 870,100,000
Design: The Rhode Island quarter honors the “Ocean State” and features a vintage sailboat gliding through Rhode Island’s famous
Narragansett Bay and an image of the Pell Bridge in the background.
Vermont
Statehood: March 4, 1791 Coin Release: August 6, 2001 Release Order: 14 Total Mintage for Circulation: 882,804,000
Design: The Vermont quarter features Camel’s Hump Mountain with an image of maple trees with sap buckets in the forefront. The coin also
bears the inscription “Freedom and Unity.”
Kentucky
Statehood: June 1, 1792 Coin Release: October 15, 2001 Release Order: 15 Total Mintage for Circulation: 723,564,000
Design: The Kentucky quarter features the stately mansion, Federal Hill, with an inscription that reads, “My Old Kentucky Home.” A
thoroughbred racehorse is positioned behind a fence in the foreground of the quarter.
2002
Tennessee
Statehood: June 1, 1796 Coin Release: January 2, 2002 Release Order: 16 Total Mintage for Circulation: 648,068,000
Design: The Tennessee quarter celebrates the state’s contributions to the Nation’s musical heritage. The design incorporates musical
instruments and a score with the inscription “Musical Heritage.” Three stars represent Tennessee’s three regions and the
instruments symbolize each region’s distinct musical style.
Ohio
Statehood: March 1, 1803 Coin Release: March 11, 2002 Release Order: 17 Total Mintage for Circulation: 632,032,000
Design: The Ohio quarter honors the state’s contribution to the history of aviation, depicting an early aircraft and an astronaut,
superimposed as a group on the outline of the state. The design also includes the inscription “Birthplace of Aviation Pioneers.”
Louisiana
Statehood: April 30, 1812 Coin Release: May 20, 2002 Release Order: 18 Total Mintage for Circulation: 764,204,000
Design: The Louisiana quarter displays the image of Louisiana’s state bird—the pelican, a trumpet with musical notes, and the outline of the
Louisiana Purchase territory, along with the inscription “Louisiana Purchase.”
INDIANA
Statehood: December 11, 1816 Coin Release: August 2, 2002 Release Order: 19 Total Mintage for Circulation: 689,800,000
Design: The Indiana quarter represents the state pride in the famous Indianapolis 500 race. The design features the image of a race car
superimposed on an outline of the state with the inscription “Crossroads of America.” The design also includes 19 stars signifying
Indiana as the 19th state admitted into the Union.
MISSISSIPPI
Statehood: December 10, 1817 Coin Release: October 15, 2002 Release Order: 20 Total Mintage for Circulation: 579,600,000
Design: The Mississippi quarter showcases the beauty and elegance of the state flower, combining the blossoms and leaves of two magnolias
with the inscription “The Magnolia State.”
24 5O STATE QUARTERS® REPORT l 1999 - 2008 l 10 YEARS OF HONORING OUR NATION’S HISTORY AND HERITAGE
2003
Illinois
Statehood: December 3, 1818 Coin Release: January 2, 2003 Release Order: 21 Total Mintage for Circulation: 463,200,000
Design: The Illinois quarter design depicts a young Abraham Lincoln within the outline of the state. A farm scene and the Chicago skyline
appear on the left and to the right of the state’s outline. Twenty-one stars border the coin, signifying Illinois as the 21st state to be
admitted into the Union.
ALABAMA
Statehood: June 15, 1836 Coin Release: March 17, 2003 Release Order: 22 Total Mintage for Circulation: 457,400,000
Design: The Alabama quarter design features an image of Helen Keller with her name in English, and in a reduced-size version of Braille.
The Alabama quarter is the first U.S. circulating coin to feature Braille. An Alabama long leaf pine branch and magnolias grace the
sides of the design, and a “Spirit of Courage” banner underlines the central image.
Maine
Statehood: March 15, 1820 Coin Release: June 2, 2003 Release Order: 23 Total Mintage for Circulation: 448,800,000
Design: The Maine quarter design incorporates a rendition of the Pemaquid Point Light atop a granite coast and of a schooner at sea.
MISSOURI
Statehood: August 10, 1821 Coin Release: August 4, 2003 Release Order: 24 Total Mintage for Circulation: 453,200,000
Design: The Missouri quarter depicts Lewis and Clark’s historic return to St. Louis down the Missouri River, with the Jefferson National
Expansion Memorial (Gateway Arch) in the background. The quarter is inscribed “Corps of Discovery 1804-2004.”
Arkansas
Statehood: June 15, 1836 Coin Release: October 20, 2003 Release Order: 25 Total Mintage for Circulation: 457,800,000
Design: The Arkansas quarter design bears the image of rice stalks, a diamond and a mallard gracefully flying above a lake.
2004
MICHIGAN
Statehood: January 26, 1837 Coin Release: January 26, 2004 Release Order: 26 Total Mintage for Circulation: 459,600,000
Design: The Michigan quarter depicts the outline of the state and the Great Lakes system. The quarter is inscribed “Great Lakes State.”
FLORIDA
Statehood: March 3, 1845 Coin Release: March 29, 2004 Release Order: 27 Total Mintage for Circulation: 481,800,000
Design: The Florida quarter design incorporates a 16th-century Spanish galleon, a space shuttle, strip of land with Sabal palm trees and the
inscription “Gateway to Discovery.”
TEXAS
Statehood: December 29, 1845 Coin Release: June 1, 2004 Release Order: 28 Total Mintage for Circulation: 541,800,000
Design: The Texas quarter’s reverse design depicts a star superimposed on the state’s outline and the inscription, “The Lone Star State.” The
lariat encircling the design is symbolic of the cattle and cowboy history of Texas, as well as the frontier spirit that tamed the land.
Iowa
Statehood: December 28, 1846 Coin Release: August 30, 2004 Release Order: 29 Total Mintage for Circulation: 465,200,000
Design: The Iowa quarter design features a one-room schoolhouse with a teacher and students planting a tree, and the inscriptions
“Foundation in Education” and “Grant Wood.” The design is based on “Arbor Day,” a painting by Grant Wood, who was born near
Anamosa, Iowa.
Wisconsin
Statehood: May 29, 1848 Coin Release: October 25, 2004 Release Order: 30 Total Mintage for Circulation: 453,200,000
Design: The Wisconsin design depicts an agricultural theme featuring a cow, a round of cheese and an ear of corn. The design also bears an
inscription of the state motto, “Forward.”
25
2005
California
Statehood: September 9, 1850 Coin Release: January 31, 2005 Release Order: 31 Total Mintage for Circulation: 520,400,000
Design: Nicknamed the “Golden State,” California’s quarter depicts naturalist and conservationist John Muir admiring Yosemite Valley’s
monolithic granite headwall known as “Half Dome” and also contains a soaring California condor. The coin bears the inscriptions
“John Muir” and “Yosemite Valley.”
Minnesota
Statehood: May 11, 1858 Coin Release: April 4, 2005 Release Order: 32 Total Mintage for Circulation: 488,000,000
Design: The Minnesota quarter design features a tree-lined lake with two people fishing, a loon on the water, and a textured outline of the state
surrounding its nickname, “Land of 10,000 Lakes.”
Oregon
Statehood: February 14, 1859 Coin Release: June 6, 2005 Release Order: 33 Total Mintage for Circulation: 720,200,000
Design: The Oregon coin design features a portion of Crater Lake, the deepest lake in the United States, viewed from the south-southwest
rim. The design incorporates Wizard Island, as well as Watchman and Hillman Peaks on the lake’s rim and conifers. The coin bears
the inscription “Crater Lake.”
Kansas
Statehood: January 29, 1861 Coin Release: August 29, 2005 Release Order: 34 Total Mintage for Circulation: 563,400,000
Design: The Kansas commemorative quarter incorporates two of the state’s most beloved symbols, the state animal and flower, the buffalo
and the sunflower.
West Virginia
Statehood: June 20, 1863 Coin Release: October 14, 2005 Release Order: 35 Total Mintage for Circulation: 721,600,000
Design: This West Virginia quarter captures the scenic beauty of the state with its depiction of the New River and the New River Gorge
Bridge. The coin bears the inscription “New River Gorge.”
2006
Nevada
Statehood: October 31, 1864 Coin Release: January 31, 2006 Release Order: 36 Total Mintage for Circulation: 589,800,000
Design: The Nevada quarter depicts a trio of wild mustangs, the sun rising behind snow-capped mountains, bordered by sagebrush and a
banner that reads “The Silver State.”
Nebraska
Statehood: March 1, 1867 Coin Release: April 3, 2006 Release Order: 37 Total Mintage for Circulation: 594,400,000
Design: The Nebraska quarter depicts an ox-drawn covered wagon carrying pioneers in the foreground and Chimney Rock, the natural
wonder that rises from the valley of North Platte River, measuring 445 feet from base to tip. The sun is in full view behind the wagon.
The coin also bears the inscription “Chimney Rock.”
Colorado
Statehood: August 1, 1876 Coin Release: June 14, 2006 Release Order: 38 Total Mintage for Circulation: 569,000,000
Design: The Colorado quarter depicts a sweeping view of the state’s rugged Rocky Mountains with evergreen trees and a banner carrying the
inscription “Colorful Colorado.”
North Dakota
Statehood: November 2, 1889 Coin Release: August 28, 2006 Release Order: 39 Total Mintage for Circulation: 664,800,000
Design: The North Dakota quarter depicts a pair of grazing American bison in the foreground with a sunset view of the rugged buttes and
canyons that help define the state’s Badlands region in the background.
South Dakota
Statehood: November 2, 1889 Coin Release: November 6, 2006 Release Order: 40 Total Mintage for Circulation: 510,800,000
Design: The South Dakota quarter features an image of the state bird, a Chinese ring-necked pheasant, in flight above a depiction of the
Mount Rushmore National Monument, featuring the faces of four American Presidents: George Washington, Thomas Jefferson,
Theodore Roosevelt and Abraham Lincoln. The design is bordered by heads of wheat.
26 5O STATE QUARTERS® REPORT l 1999 - 2008 l 10 YEARS OF HONORING OUR NATION’S HISTORY AND HERITAGE
2007
Montana
Statehood: November 8, 1889 Coin Release: January 29, 2007 Release Order: 41 Total Mintage for Circulation: 513,240,000
Design: The reverse of Montana’s quarter features a bison skull depicted above the diverse Montana landscape with the inscription “Big Sky
Country.”
Washington
Statehood: November 11, 1889 Coin Release: April 2, 2007 Release Order: 42 Total Mintage for Circulation: 545,200,000
Design: The reverse of Washington’s quarter features a king salmon breaching the water in front of majestic Mount Rainier. The coin bears
the inscription “The Evergreen State.”
Idaho
Statehood: July 3, 1890 Coin Release: June 4, 2007 Release Order: 43 Total Mintage for Circulation: 581,400,000
Design: The reverse of Idaho’s quarter features the Peregrine Falcon imposing its presence above an outline of the state.
The coin bears an inscription of the state motto “Esto Perpetua” (“May it be Forever”).
Wyoming
Statehood: July 10, 1890 Coin Release: September 4, 2007 Release Order: 44 Total Mintage for Circulation: 564,400,000
Design: The reverse of Wyoming’s quarter features a bucking horse and rider with the inscription “The Equality State.”
Utah
Statehood: January 4, 1896 Coin Release: November 5, 2007 Release Order: 45 Total Mintage for Circulation: 508,200,000
Design: The reverse of Utah’s quarter features two locomotives moving toward the golden spike that joined the Central Pacific and Union Pacific
railroads, linking East to West and transforming both the Utah Territory and the Nation with the inscription “Crossroads of the West.”
2006
Oklahoma
Statehood: November 16, 1907 Coin Release: January 28, 2008 Release Order: 46 Total Mintage for Circulation: 416,600,000
Design: The Oklahoma quarter features an image of the state bird, the Scissortail Flycatcher, in flight with its distinctive tail feathers spread.
The bird is soaring over the state wildflower, the Indian Blanket, backed by a field of similar wildflowers.
New Mexico
Statehood: January 6, 1912 Coin Release: April 7, 2008 Release Order: 47 Total Mintage for Circulation: 488,600,000
Design: The reverse of New Mexico’s quarter features a Zia sun symbol over a topographical outline of the state with the inscription “Land
of Enchantment.”
Arizona
Statehood: February 14, 1912 Coin Release: June 2, 2008 Release Order: 48 Total Mintage for Circulation: 509,600,000
Design: The Arizona quarter features an image of the Grand Canyon with a Saguaro cactus in the foreground. A banner reading “Grand
Canyon State” separates the two images to signify that the Saguaro cactus does not grow in the Grand Canyon.
Alaska
Statehood: January 3, 1959 Coin Release: August 25, 2008 Release Order: 49 Total Mintage for Circulation: 505,800,000
Design: The reverse of the Alaska quarter features a grizzly bear emerging from the waters clutching a salmon in its jaw. The coin’s design
includes the North Star displayed above the inscription “The Great Land.”
Hawaii
Statehood: August 21, 1959 Coin Release: November 3, 2008 Release Order: 50 Total Mintage for Circulation: 517,600,000
Design: The reverse of Hawaii’s quarter features Hawaiian monarch King Kamehameha I stretching his hand toward the eight major
Hawaiian Islands. The coin bears an inscription of the state motto “UA MAU KE EA O KA ‘ĀINA I KA PONO,” (“The life of the
land is perpetuated in righteousness”).